## Heming Wang

474 Dreese Laboratories 2015 Neil Avenue The Ohio State University Columbus, OH 43202, USA Phone: 614-286-7961 wang.11401@osu.edu

Homepage: whmrtm.github.io

# **SUMMARY**

PROFESSIONAL My name is Heming Wang, and I am currently a fifth-year Ph.D. student in Computer Science and Engineering at the Ohio State University, advised by Prof. DeLiang Wang. My research interests focus on speech enhancement, self-supervised learning and generative AI.

## RESEARCH **EXPERIENCES**

Research Intern May-August 2023

Tencent AI Lab Seattle, Washington, United States

• Nearfield sound resynthesis with vocoder / codec / self-supervised learning models

Research Intern May-August 2022

Microsoft Inc.

Seattle, Washington, United States

• Use self-supervised learning to improve generative performance of speech repre-

Research Intern May-August 2021

Microsoft Inc.

Seattle, Washington, United States

• Use self-supervised learning to improve robust automatic speech recognition

Research Intern May-August 2020

Elevoc Inc. Shenzhen, Guangdong, China

- Efficient network for bandwidth extension on mobile devices
- Bandwidth extension for bone-conducted speech

#### Graduate Research Assistant

The Ohio State University Columbus, Ohio, USA

August 2018 - Present

- Speech enhancement
- Self-supervised learning
- Generative AI

### Graduate Research Assistant

August 2016 - May 2018

University of Waterloo Waterloo, Ontario, Canada

- Real-time signal processing for ultrasound
- Empirical mode decomposition for signal analysis
- Bayesian methods for blind source separation

Research Intern May-August 2016

AISpeech Suzhou, Jiangsu, China

- Chinese singing voice synthesis
  - Part-of-speech tagging

#### Undergraduate Research Assistant

May-August 2015

University of Waterloo Waterloo, Ontario Canada

- Formant synthesis for English vowels
- Real-time spectrum analysis using MyDAQ
- **PUBLICATIONS** M. Yang, C. Zhang, Y. Xu, Z. Xu, **H. Wang**, B. Raj and D. Yu. "uSee: Unified Speech Enhancement and Editing with Conditional Diffusion Models." in *arXiv* preprint arXiv:2310.00900, 2023.
  - L. Zhang, Y. Qian, L. Yu, **H. Wang**, X. Wang, H. Yang, L. Zhou, S. Liu, Y. Qian and M. Zeng. "Diffusion Conditional Expectation Model for Efficient and Robust Target Speech Extraction." in arXiv preprint arXiv:2309.13874, 2023.
  - **H.** Wang and D. L. Wang. "A Time-Frequency Domain Multi-Path Network for Packet Loss Concealment." in submission to *IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (ICASSP), 2023.
  - **H. Wang**, M. Yu, H. Zhang, C. Zhang, Z. Xu, M. Yang, Y. Zhang and D. Yu. "Unifying Robustness and Fidelity: A Comprehensive Study of Pretrained Generative Methods for Speech Enhancement in Adverse Conditions." in *arXiv* preprint *arXiv*:2309.09028, 2023.
  - Z. Xu, Y. Xu, V. Kothapally, **H. Wang**, M. Yang and D. Yu. "SpatialCodec: Neural Spatial Speech Coding" in *arXiv preprint arXiv:2309.07432*, 2023.
  - **H.** Wang and D. L. Wang. "Cross-Domain Diffusion Based Speech Enhancement for Very Noisy Speech." in *IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (ICASSP), 2023.
  - **H. Wang**, Yao. Q, H. Yang, N. Kanda, P. Wang, T. Yoshioka, X. Wang, Y. Wang, S. Liu, Z. Chen and others. "DATA2VEC-SG: Improving Self-Supervised Learning Representations for Speech Generation Tasks." in *IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (ICASSP), 2023.
  - **H. Wang**, X. Zhang, and D. L. Wang. "Fusing Bone-conduction and Air-conduction Sensors for Complex-Domain Speech Enhancement." *IEEE/ACM Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing* (**IEEE/ACM TASLP**), Vol. 30, pp. 3134-3143. 2022.
  - Y. Zhang, **H. Wang**, and D. L. Wang, "Densely-connected Convolutional Recurrent Network for Fundamental Frequency Estimation in Noisy Speech," in the 23th Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association (**INTERSPEECH**), pp. 401-405, 2022.
  - **H. Wang**, Y. Qian, X. Wang, Y. Wang, C. Wang, S. Liu, T. Yoshioka, J. Li and D. L. Wang, "Improving Noise Robustness of Contrastive Speech Representation Learning with Speech Reconstruction," in *IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (**ICASSP**), pp. 6062-6066, 2021.

- Y. Wang, J. Li, **H. Wang**, Y. Qian, C. Wang and Y. Wu, "Wav2vec-Switch: Contrastive Learning from Original-noisy Speech Pairs for Robust Speech Recognition," in *IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (ICASSP), pp. 7097-7101, 2021.
- **H. Wang**, X. Zhang and D. L. Wang, "Attention-based Fusion for Bone-conducted and Air-conducted Speech Enhancement in the Complex Domain," in *IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (ICASSP), pp. 7757-7761, 2021.
- **H. Wang** and D. L. Wang, "Cross-domain Speech Enhancement With A Neural Cascade Architecture," in *IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (**ICASSP**), pp. 7862-7866, 2021.
- **H. Wang** and D. L. Wang, "Neural Cascade Architecture with Triple-domain Loss for Speech Enhancement," in *IEEE/ACM Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing* (**IEEE/ACM TASLP**), vol. 30, pp. 734-743, 2021.
- **H. Wang** and D. L. Wang, "Towards Robust Speech Super-resolution," in *IEEE/ACM Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing* (**IEEE/ACM TASLP**), vol. 29, pp. 2058-2066, 2021.
- **H.** Wang and D. L. Wang. "Time-Frequency Loss for CNN Based Speech Super-Resolution," in *IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing* (ICASSP), pp. 861-865, 2020.
- **H. Wang**, R. Mann, and E. R. Vrscay, "A Diffusion-Based Two-Dimensional Empirical Mode Decomposition Algorithm for Image Analysis," in *International Conference Image Analysis and Recognition* (ICIAR), pp. 293-305, 2018.

#### **EDUCATION**

**The Ohio State University**, Columbus, OH, USA August 2018 - Present Advisor: Prof. DeLiang Wang Ph.D. student, Computer Science and Engineering

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Canada Au Advisor: Prof. Richard Mann & Prof. Edward Vrscay Master of Mathematics, Applied Mathematics

August 2016 - May 2018

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Canada Bachelor of Science, Physics & Computer Science Minor

August 2014 - May 2016

**Harbin Institute of Technology**, Harbin, HL, China Electric Science and Technology

August 2012 - May 2014

COMPUTER SKILLS

 $Python,\ C++,\ Bash,\ MATLAB,\ Pytorch,\ Tensorflow,\ Keras.$ 

AWARDS University Fellowship

# **Entrance Scholarship**

Department of Physics & Astronomy, University of Waterloo

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Reviewer: IEEE/ACM Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing, IEEE Internet of Things Journal, Cybernetics and Systems, IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing

2014